Sampo Pesonen

Front-End += Game Developer





Summary

Programmer / Artist with years of experience in indie development. Freelanced .for multiple clients in gaming and web development, creating games, WordPress sites, and static websites.

Skilled in HTML, CSS, JS, and C#.

Social, adaptable, and strong in communication and teamwork.

Experience

Game Developer – Indie Studio

Piston Media (Finland) 2018 – Present (part time)

- Developed gameplay systems in Unity and Godot
- 2 published titles on Steam
- 3 asset packs published on the Unity Asset Store
- 1 mobile game in development

2nd Line Service Desk Specialist

Planeetta Internet Oy (Finland) 01.2021 - 05.2024

- Solved technical issues for clients
- Databases, site transfers, DNS & nameserver modifications
- Helped 1st line agents with more basic technical issues

Web Developer & Graphical Designer

Advertising Agency Synergia (Finland) 09.2013 - 12.2013

- · Web development for clients
- Video shooting & editing for marketing purposes
- Designed print marketing materials

Web Developer Admin (Online Shop)

City Plus Oy (Finland) 06.2013 - 08.2013

- Added new products for eStore and updated old ones.
- Contacted product factories for offers for products to sell in the eStore

Web Developer Support

MarujaLimon S.L. (Spain) 03.2012 - 07.2013

- · Created Wordpress sites for various clients.
- Maintained websites by updating content and installing required plugins

Education

Bachelor of Business Information Technology

HAMK University of Applied Sciences 09.2008 - 04.2013

Entrepreneurship and Game Development Studies

Metropolia University of Applied Sciences 01.2017 - 12.2017

Skills

- Unity (C#)
- Godot (GDScript)
- HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- AI, OOP, Game Systems
- Git, GitHub
- · Linux, terminal, and workstations
- WHM + WHMCS & cPanel

Languages

- Finnish (Native)
- English (Full professional proficiency)
- Spanish (Professional working proficiency)

Certificates

- Responsive Web Design
- · Elements of Al